ILGWU Research Department Collected Documents 5780/056
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Research Department Collected Documents
1906-1948
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/056
6.83 cubic feet
6.8 linear ft.
Administrative records, correspondence, financial reports, minutes (administrative records).
Much of the material concerns various strikes, including the New York cloakmakers' strikes of 1926 and 1929, as well as the "Protocol of Peace" of 1910. There are some additional items dealing with the New York Cloak Joint Board. A good portion of the material is administrative in nature.
3676411
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
D. Mordente, October 13, 2008
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 09, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Formed in 1937, the Research Department of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU) supported the administrative operations of the Union and coordinated the ILGWU's investigative operations. It provided union leaders with information on wages, working conditions, economic conditions, and other matters in the women's garment industry; analyzed information for the union; and monitored developments in the industry.
In addition to providing research for union leadership, Research Department staff prepared materials for Congressional testimony, presented cases on behalf of local unions to the War Labor Board, and worked to administer the Fair Labor Standards Act. At times, the director of the Research Department represented the ILGWU in national forums.
The Department also maintained an extensive library, collecting and housing documents from Union administrative staff that were deemed substantive and of lasting value to the Union, whether produced internally or externally. The information gathered by the Department was of particular value during labor disputes and contract negotiations.
Lazare Teper was the founding director of the ILGWU's Research Department, working in that position from 1937 to 1980. Born in Russia sometime between 1906 and 1908, Teper later studied at the University of Paris and earned his doctorate at Johns Hopkins University. He died in New York City in 1985.
Scope and Contents
The Research Department records reflect the department's varied functions, documenting its role in gathering and analyzing information for international and local union leadership, representing the union before government and labor organizations, and gathering materials of research, and oftentimes historical, value. Some segments of the records focus on one aspect of the department's work, and others include documentation across the department's functions.
Research Department director Lazare Teper's papers, for example, include files relating to the Wage Stabilization Board (5780/105). The department also maintained records focused on the National Coat and Suit Industry Board (statements of receipts and disbursements, label division reports, meetings minutes, bulletins to members, and other reports and resolutions), as well as some related legal files (5780/123). Also among the documents collected by the Research Department are the New York Coat and Suit Industry Reports between 1934 and 1960. (5780/168)
Parts of the Research Department records consist primarily of collected documents from ILGWU affiliates. In this way, they resemble and, in some instances, complement the parts of the Archives Department Records (5780/121, 5780/121 PUBS), records generated by local unions (Series III), and the general collection of ILGWU publications (5780 PUBS). Research Department records of this kind contain records of predecessor unions to the ILGWU and ILGWU local union records (5780/045), or the annual report, "Conditions in the Women's Clothing Industry" (5780/078).
Other parts of the Research Department records document all of the department's functions. These records include financial and administrative reports, meeting minutes, and correspondence (5780/056, 5780/209), collected printed material (5780/168), and ILGWU statements on issues related to the garment industry (5780/209).
The Research Deparment collected documents included financial and administrative reports, meeting minutes, correspondence, and other materials documenting the activities and interests of the ILGWU Research Department. Much of the material concerns various strikes, including the New York cloakmakers' strikes of 1926 and 1929, as well as the "Protocol of Peace" of 1910. There are some additional items dealing with the New York Cloak Joint Board. A good portion of the material is administrative in nature. Notable individuals represented in this collection include: Louis Brandeis; August Claessens; Julius Henry Cohen; A. J. Muste; Benjamin Schlesinger; Norman Thomas; Alexander Trachtenberg; and B.C. Vladeck. Organizations include various joint boards of the union throughout the United States and the Workers Party of America. Subjects include communism and the union; conventions of the ILGWU; labor negotiations; labor disputes; strikes (particularly in New York City); unemployment insurance; and wages in the garment industry.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/045: ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/078: ILGWU Research Department Reports 5780/105: ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/123: ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/168: ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/209: ILGWU Research Department Records
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Communism -- United States; Unemployment insurance -- United States; Labor unions and communism -- United States; Labor union locals.; Strikes and lockouts -- Clothing trade -- New York (State) -- New York; Strikes and lockouts -- Clothing trade -- United States; Labor disputes -- New York (State) -- New York; Labor disputes -- United States; Wages -- Clothing workers -- United States; Brandeis, Louis Dembitz, 1856-1941.; Claessens, August, 1885-1954.; Cohen, Julius Henry, b. 1873.; Muste, Abraham John, 1885-1967.; Schlesinger, Benjamin, 1876-1932; Trachtenberg, Alexander.; Vladeck, B.(Baruch Charney), 1886-1935.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Research Dept.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. New York Cloak Joint Board.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Convention.; Workers Party of America.
3676411
- Communism, Workers Party of America, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 1a)
  Scope and Contents
  Incl. conference communications from Industrial Council & from Trade Union Educational League.
- Communism, Workers Party of America, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 1b)
  Oct. 15, 1921. Report on Communist meeting re organizing in New York Joint Board.
- Communism, Workers Party of America, 1920-1929 (Box 1, Folder 1c)
  Incl. "Statement on the Needle Trade Situation;" "Proposed Plan for a Shop Delegates System of Organization for the ILGWU
- Conference on One Union for Cloakmakers and Dressmakers, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Draft resolution.
- Conventions, Union, 1917-1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  GEB report to special convention re Local 1 controversy; brief submitted to Appeal Comm. of GEB re election of delegates by William Bloom & Harry Wagner.
- Conventions, Union, 1922-1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Incl. declaration of principles by the Progressive delegates to the convention; list of delegates.
- Conventions, Union, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Joint statement by delegates of Locals & of Dressmakers Jt. Bds. of N.Y. & Chicago re refusal of convention to seat delegates; Louis Hyman statement; list of delegates.
- Conventions, Union, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Incl. convention call.
- Conventions, Union, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Ballot for N.Y. vice presidents.
- General Executive Board, 1912-1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Reports by Morris Sigman (1912) and George Wishnak (1937).
- Governor's Advisory Council, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, NYC, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Reports, statements of Union, management and commission.
- Governor's Advisory Council, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, NYC, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Copies of correspondence. bet. Jt. Bd. & Governor's Office, memo to Industrial Council of the Cloak, Suit & Skirt Mfrs., Inc.
- Joint Boards, Boston, Jt. Bd. Cloak and Skirt Makers Union, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Corres. bet. Ladies' Garment Mfrs. Assoc. & Jt. Bd.; 1921 strike calls.
- Jt. Bds., Boston, Jt. Bd. Cloak and Skirt Makers Union [folder 1 of 2], 1913-1923 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Minutes.
- Jt. Bds., Boston, Jt. Bd. Cloak and Skirt Makers Union [folder 2 of 2], 1913-1923 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Jt. Bds., Boston, Jt. Bd. Cloak and Skirt Makers Union, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Oct. 7, 1913. Minutes of investigation committee.
- Jt. Bds., Boston, Jt. Bd. Cloak and Skirt Makers Union, 1920-1923 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Financial reports.
- Jt. Bds., Boston, Jt. Bd. Cloak and Skirt Makers Union, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Mar-June 1907. Financial contributions to strike fund; by-laws of Boston Cloak Mfrs. Assoc.
- Jt. Bds., Boston, Jt. Bd. Cloak and Skirt Makers Union, 1934-1939 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Incl. NLRB case re Boston Maid, Inc.
- Jt. Bds., Cleveland Joint Board, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  April 1921, Decision of Bd of Referees in Cloak, Suit & Skirt Industry.
- Jt. Bds., Cleveland Jt. Bd., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Memo concerning health & decency budget required for a wage earner's family in Cleveland; incl. research material.
- Jt. Bds., Cleveland Jt. Bd., 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Incl. releases & telegrams.
- Jt. Bds., Chicago Joint Board, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Memo to S. Hamburger (Union accountant) re costs of injunction against Union in 1924 strike.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  June 30, 1930. Injunction by Brooklyn Ladies' Garment Mfrs. Assoc. against Union and Associations.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Corres. with International Union Bank re loans and investments.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1912-1942 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Incl. Records re loans, bank book of Jt. Bd.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Financial reports; incl. statement of expenses for 1919 general strike.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1932-1935 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Form ltrs.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Dec. 13, 1926. Decision by Paul Abelson (impartial chairman).
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1923-1930 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1906-1933 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Demands, list of mfrs., conference report (1933).
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1924-1927 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Notices of meetings, incl. some from left-wing.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Reports on investigation in the waist shops controlled by the Union (1923) & on "Investigation of the Dress Industry" by Nathan Wolf (1924).
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  May 1920-Mar. 1921. Reports of American Association District.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Mar. 18, 1921. Report of Brooklyn Office.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1920-1923 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  June 1920-July 1923. Reports of Independent Reefer Dept.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Dec. 1919-May 1923. Reports of Protective Division.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  May 1920-May 1921. Reports of Skirt & Dress Dept.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union. (n.d.) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  The Crisis and the Cloakmakers, statement by executive board.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1924-1929 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Yiddish. Incl. list of General Strike Committees & resolutions.
- Jt. Bds., N.Y. Cloak, Skirt, Dress and Reefer Makers Union, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Incl. report on Garment Industries Board of Trade, Inc. & memo to Nat'l. Coat & Suit Recovery Bd. containing list of Associations having collective agreements with the Union.
- J. Bds., Jt. Bd. Cloak and Skirt Makers' Union, Philadelphia, Pa., 1920 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Incl. financial report & memo concerning increase in cost of living in Phila.
- Lefkovits, Samuel, 1920-1924 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Local 1, NYC, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Incl. hearings of Special Committee, appointed by Exec. Bd., re allegations by Pure and Simple Trade Union League against administration (Feb. 5 & 9, 1923).
- Local 1, NYC, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Notification to members of hearings re membership in Trade Union Educational League (TUEL) and Committee of Fifty (formerly Pure & Simple Trade Union League); minutes of hearing (Nov. 10, 1923) & notes of meetings (Dec. 15 & 31, 1923).
- Local 1, NYC, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 17a)
  Yiddish. Statement by Samuel Zeldin & Isidor Steiner re GEB policy on TUEL membership? statement by Local exec. bd. members.
- Local 1; 1932. Form letters. (Box 2, Folder 17b)
- Local 1, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Org. comm. minutes (Feb. 2, 1933); Declaration of the Trade Union Center Group & United Progressive League (Nov. 4, 1933); Open Letter re week-work to Local 9 from Local 1 (July 16, 1933).
- Local 2, NYC, 1917-1928 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Jurisdictional dispute bet. Locals 1 & 17; incl. report & recommendations of Committee of Three (Benjamin Schlesinger, S. Koldovsky & Hyman Schoolman), appointed by GEB (The Ladies Garment Worker, Dec. 1917); Gomper's telegrams (1924); "Why Local 17 Be Reinstated" (sic) by Abraham Rosenberg (1928).
- Local 2. (n.d.) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Petitions of reefer makers for the re-establishment of Local 17.
- Local 2, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Special Investigation Comm.; "Reefer Makers Memorandum In Support of Resolution #105, of the 19th Convention of the I.L.G.W.U. held in Boston, Mass. May, 1928."
- Local 2, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Aug. 28, 1928. Special Investigation Comm. minutes.
- Local 2 [folder 1 of 2], 1928 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Sept. 4 & 20, 1928. Special Investigation Comm. report of hearings.
- Local 2 [folder 2 of 2], 1928 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Local 2, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  B. Charney Vladeck statement re Local 2 elections (Jewish Daily Forward, May 18, 1930); B. Schlesinger ltr. re report of Special Committee investigation of Local 2 elections; copies of ltrs. to Special Comm. re alleged election irregularities.
- Local 9, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Louis Hyman declaration (n.d.); Declaration of Principles of Trade Union Group of Local 9 (May 1931).
- Local 9, NYC, 1914-1926 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Nov. 1914-Dec. 1926. Ledger Book.
- Local 9, NYC, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Nov. 1933. Trial material against administration of Local; incl. exhibits consisting of statements, broadsides, leaflets.
- Local 22, NYC, 1922-1936 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Conference Comm. meeting re reaffiliation of Locals 22 & 23 (Nov. 6, 1922); press releases (1936).
- Local 23, NYC, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Report on investigation of Samuel Fremed (manager).
- Local 25, 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Financial records.
- Local 33, Boston, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Report of meeting (June 19, 1939).
- Local 35, NYC (Box 3, Folder 13)
  undated documents. Lists, including members of Trade Union Educational League.
- Local 38, NYC, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Strike. Incl. correspondence. re strike, lists, statements, press releases & newspaper clippings.
- Local 48, NYC, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Resolution.
- Local 56, Boston, 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  May 1922-Feb. 1923. Financial reports.
- Local 60, NYC, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Declaration of principles for Local health & welfare plan.
- Local 64, NYC, 1912-1922 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  July 1921-Mar. 1922. Audit.
- Local 102, NYC, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  "I Accuse" by Saul Metz.
- Local 117, NYC, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Charges against J. Katz, H. Aidenland, Hyman Libow, S. Rothman, Louis Farber, William Sporn, A. Mallin, L. Klotz & L. Nickelsberg for illegal group activity incl. publication of Union Vanguard.
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Audit, Joint Committee of Action (June 24-Nov. 3, 1925).
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Declaration of Executive Boards of Locals 2, 9, 22 (Sept. 23, 1925).
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Minutes, Jt. Comm. of Action; protest against suspension of locals? statements & resolutions incl. Union pamphlet, The L Communist Plaque In Our Unions.
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Trial; charges brought by Israel Feinberg against members of Locals 2, 9, 22 w. lists of accused; statement of Special Committee appointed by Joint Board.
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 1 of 14], 1925 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Trial; transcript of proceedings of trial (June 25-July 9, 1925).
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 2 of 14], 1925 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 3 of 14], 1925 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 4 of 14], 1925 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 5 of 14], 1925 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 6 of 14], 1925 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 7 of 14], 1925 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 8 of 14], 1925 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 9 of 14], 1925 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 10 of 14], 1925 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 11 of 14], 1925 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 12 of 14], 1925 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 13 of 14], 1925 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union [folder 14 of 14], 1925 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Suit re loan by Julius Portnoy, Joseph Boruchowitz, Abe Zirlin (plaintiffs) against International Union Bank and Frederick F. Umhey (defendants) (February 15, 1927).
- Local Unions, Internal Conflict With Union, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Incl. GEB resolution suspending Locals 2, 9, 22; resolution of mass meeting, condemning Pres. Sigman.
- Manuscripts, I. Alexandrowicz and B. Mitchell [folder 1 of 2], 1946 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Descriptions of documentary material on right-left struggles in ILGWU; incl. handwritten copies of statements & news releases of 1926 Cloakmakers Strike (94 pp); "Internal Conflict Within the ILGWU" (11 pp).
- Manuscripts, I. Alexandrowicz and B. Mitchell [folder 2 of 2], 1946 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Manuscripts, Walter Nelles [folder 1 of 2], 1925 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  "Labor Injunctions," part II (pp. 79-237) and notes (pp. 21-85).
- Manuscripts, Walter Nelles [folder 2 of 2], 1925 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Manuscripts, Walter Nelles, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  "Contempt" (pp. 46-121) and notes (pp. 1-24).
- Manuscripts, Selig Perlman. (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  "Jewish Unionism, Its Birth Pangs & Contribution to the General American Labor Movement" (42 pp).
- Manuscripts, Alexander Trachtenberg, 1919-1922 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  The Cloak Strike Day By Day, A Chronological History of the Recent Conflict in the Cloak and Suit Industry.
- Manuscripts (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  "Communist Activities in the American Trade Union Movement," no author, no date; material on Communist movement, the TUEL, gleaned from various sources incl. American Labor Year Book (1923-24) & newspapers.
- Manuscripts, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  The Rise and Fall of Communism in the ILGWU, no author (12 pp).
- Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union, 1928-1929 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Dec. 28, 1928-Jan. 1, 1929. National convention reports.
- N.T.W.I.U., 1930 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  National convention reports.
- N.T.W.I.U. (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Misc. printed matter.
- New York Cloakmakers' Strike, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Reports of meetings of General Strike Committee.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Corres. & complaints by mfrs. & disposition of pending complaints by Organization Committee.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Ltrs. from August Claessens, Charles Solomon, A.J. Muste, & Norman Thomas re speaking engagements.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Exec. bd. lists.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Lists of shops, Union and non-Union; also list of shops controlled by deposed Joint Board.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Minutes of General Strike Committee &. Provisional Strike Committee.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Minutes of Joint Board meetings.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Press releases by Jt. Bd.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  General Strike Comm. reports & statements.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  "Outline of developments during the strike" (weekly newsletter).
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Statements by Morris Sigman.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Statements appearing in Freiheit & other papers.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  Incl. history of Strike; GEB order on N.Y. Cloakmakers' Union; "Pacts About the Cloak Strike;" & appeal by W. Green for contributions to strike (Oct. 18, 1926).
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  Incl. GEB statement to membership & statement of facts submitted to GEB.